haygroup.com 2014-12-28

# Global privacy policy summary

It is important that you read and understand our entire privacy policy before using the Services. The entire privacy policy can be found here. To assist you with your review of the privacy policy, we have provided below a brief introductory statement for the key sections of the privacy policy, along with a link to the relevant section of the privacy policy. We note that the summary provided below is merely a handy reference guide, and is not a substitute for reviewing the entire privacy policy. Any capitalized terms that appear, but are not defined in the introduction, have the meanings given to them elsewhere in the privacy policy.

  * When we interact with you through our Services, we collect information about you to improve our overall Services
  * We use your information to improve the value of our Services
  * You decide when to turn off cookies in your browser and whether we can use your data for marketing
  * We use security measures to protect your data
  * The information you share with us and our service providers is used to deliver our Services
  * We have tried to make our privacy policy to be like our products and services – simple and intuitive. But you can contact us with any questions you may have.

Back to Top

### Global privacy policy

LAST UPDATED: November 15, 2013

Hay Group, Inc. and its affiliates (“ **Hay Group** ”) are concerned about privacy issues and want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose information. This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with information that we collect through the websites operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “Sites”), through the software applications and online services made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “ **Apps** ”), through our social media pages and apps to which our Sites and Apps link (the “ **Social Media Pages** ”) as well as through HTML-formatted email messages that we send to you that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, including the Sites, the Apps and our Social Media Pages, the “ **Online Systems** ”), as well as information we collect through offline sources. By providing Personal Information (as defined below) to us, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

In the course of providing consulting services and related Online Systems (collectively “Consulting Services and Tools”) to its clients, Hay Group may collect, use and disclose certain Personal Information about individuals to whom the services relate (each, a “Participant”), which may include a client’s employees or other individuals. In addition to the generally applicable provisions of this Privacy Policy, please review the Consulting Services and Tools Participants section below to see important information.

Back to Top

### Safe harbor

Hay Group Inc. has certified to the Safe Harbor framework agreed to by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the EU and the US and Switzerland with respect to certain Personal Information collected by our affiliates and corporate clients located in the European Economic Area and Switzerland and transferred to Hay Group, Inc. and Hay Group Management, Inc. in the United States. Please see our Safe Harbor Statement. For additional information regarding the Safe Harbor Program, see the U.S. Dept. of Commerce web site at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. .

Back to Top

### Personal Information

**Personal Information We May Collect**

“ **Personal Information** ” is information that identifies you as an individual, including: 

  * Name
  * Postal address (including billing and shipping addresses)
  * Telephone and fax number
  * Email address
  * Account ID and password
  * Credit and debit card number
  * Resume or CV information
  * Mobile device photos, contacts or address book information 

If you submit any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Online Systems, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**How We May Collect Personal Information**

We and our service providers may collect Personal Information in a variety of ways, including: 

  * **Through the Online Systems** : We may collect Personal Information through the Online Systems, e.g., when you create an account, download a publication or make a purchase.  
Offline: We may collect Personal Information from you offline, such as when you attend one of our training courses or conferences or another event, participate in employee compensation, effectiveness, talent and leadership surveys, diagnostics and assessments, or contact us over the telephone.
  * **From Other Sources** : We may receive your Personal Information from other sources, such as public databases; joint marketing partners; social media platforms; your employer’s Human Resources department or other personnel managers when your employer engages us to provide services; people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected on social media platforms; and other third parties. For example, if you elect to connect your social media account to your Site account, certain Personal Information from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include Personal Information that is part of your profile or your friends’ profiles. 

.

**How We May Use Personal Information**

We may use Personal Information: 

  * To respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to provide you with a subscription or to allow you to download publications.
  * To send administrative information to you, for example, information regarding the Online Systems and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.
  * To complete and fulfill your purchase, for example, to process your payments, have your order delivered to you, communicate with you regarding your purchase and provide you with related customer service.
  * To allow you to register for training courses, conferences or other events.
  * To allow you to create an account to access restricted parts of the Online Systems.
  * To provide services to your employer (for example, if you are designated as a contact person by your employer).
  * To send you marketing communications that we believe may be of interest to you.
  * To request your feedback through a customer satisfaction or market research survey.
  * To personalize your experience on the Online Systems by presenting products and offers tailored to you.
  * To allow you to participate in sweepstakes, contests and similar promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules, which could contain additional information about how we use and disclose your Personal Information, so we suggest that you read these rules carefully.
  * To facilitate social sharing functionality.
  * To allow you to send messages to a friend through the Online Systems. By using this functionality, you are telling us that you are entitled to use and provide us with your friend’s name and email address.
  * To produce research, statistical norms, benchmarking and publishing studies and articles.
  * For our business purposes, such as, data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new products, enhancing, improving or modifying our Online Systems, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

**How Personal Information May Be Disclosed**

Your Personal Information may be disclosed:

  * To our affiliates for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Hay Group, Inc. is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Information.
  * To our third party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, marketing, email delivery, credit card processing, auditing and other similar services.
  * To third parties as needed to fulfill your request or transaction, such as our business partners, financial institutions, and Customs or other government authorities.
  * To or as instructed by your employer (for example, if you are designated as a contact person by your employer).
  * To third parties with whom we offer co-branded products or services (“Co-Branding Partner”). In some cases Hay Group does not share your Personal Information with the Co-Branding Partner; instead it directly collects the information from you. We encourage you to read the Co-Branding Partner’s privacy policy to understand how it will handle information about you.
  * By you, on forums, wikis, blogs, profile pages and blogs and other services to which you are able to post information and materials (including, without limitation, our Social Media Pages). Please note that any information you post or disclose through these services will become public information, and may be available to users of the Online Systems and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the Online Systems.
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

Back to Top

### Consulting services and tools participants

In addition to any of the types of Personal Information listed above, Hay Group may collect personal information from individuals in the course of providing Consulting Services and Tools to our clients. The information we collect from or about Participants in our Consulting Services and Tools include the following Personal Information from you or others:

  * Results of employee compensation, effectiveness, talent and leadership surveys, diagnostics and assessments
  * Human resources information (such as your salary, job sizing, benefits, total rewards statements and organizational structure and alignment)
  * Your gender, race, ethnic origin, nationality and marital status, and other sensitive information that your employer (or other organization with which you have a relationship) may ask us to collect as part of an assessment or survey; your provision of this information is optional and we collect it if you choose to provide this optional information when you complete the assessment or survey. 

We collect, use and disclose Participant Personal Information to provide services to our clients (i.e. your employer or other organization with which you have a relationship that has asked you or others to participate in the services we provide). We will only collect, use or disclose Participant Personal Information as instructed by our client. Part of the services provide to our clients includes using Participant Personal Information we collect to provide research, statistical norms, and benchmarking.

Back to Top

### Other Information

**Other Information We May Collect**

“ **Other Information** ” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual, such as: 

  * Browser and device information
  * App usage data
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic information and other information provided by you
  * Aggregated information

**How We May Collect Other Information**

We and our third party service providers may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * **Through your browser or device** : Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version and the name and version of the Online Systems (such as the App) you are using. We use this information to ensure that the Online Systems function properly.
  * **Through your use of the App** : When you download and use the App, we and our service providers may track and collect App usage data, such as the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number.

.

  * **Using cookies** : Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, time spent on the Online Systems, pages visited, language preferences, and other anonymous traffic data. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser. However, if you choose to disable this function, your experience at the Site may be diminished and some features may not work as they were intended. Please see our Cookie policy for more information.

  * **Using pixel tags and other similar technologies** : Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used in connection with some Online Systems to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Online Systems (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Online Systems and response rates.
  * **IP Address** : Your “ **IP Address** ” is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP Address may be identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user accesses the Online Systems, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications and other services. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels of the Online Systems, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Online Systems.
  * **Physical Location** : We may collect the physical location of your device by, for example, using satellite, cell phone tower or WiFi signals. We may use your device’s physical location to provide you with personalized location-based services and content. We may also share your device’s physical location, combined with information about what advertisements you viewed and other information we collect, with our marketing partners to enable them to provide you with more personalized content and to study the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. In some instances, you may be permitted to allow or deny such uses and/or sharing of your device’s location, but if you choose to deny such uses and/or sharing, we and/or our marketing partners may not be able to provide you with the applicable personalized services and content.
  * **From you** : Information such as your location, as well as other information, such as your areas of interest, preferred newsletters and online community choices, is collected when you voluntarily provide this information. Unless combined with Personal Information, this information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Online Systems.
  * **By aggregating information** : Aggregated Personal Information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Online Systems, (for example, we may aggregate Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code).

**How We May Use and Disclose Other Information**

Please note that we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we may use it as described in “How We May Collect Other Information” section above, as well as for all the purposes for which we use and disclose Personal Information.

In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information (such as combining your name with your geographical location). If we combine any Other Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information as long as it is combined.

Back to Top

### Third party services

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Online Systems link. The inclusion of a link on the Online Systems does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by our affiliates. 

Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, usage and disclosure policies and practices (including the data security practices) of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM, Twitter, LinkedIn or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including any Personal Information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with the Apps or our Social Media Pages.

Back to Top

### Third party advertisers

We may use third-party advertising companies to advertise our products and services on other websites, based on information relating to your access to and use of the Online Systems and other websites. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your device (including through use of pixel tags). If you would like more information about this practice and to learn about your choices in connection with these practices, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>.

.

Back to Top

### Security

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information within our organization. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with the “Contacting Us” section of this Privacy Policy.

Back to Top

### Choices and access

**Your choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information**

We give you many choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. You may opt-out from:

  * Receiving electronic communications from us: If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails from Hay Group, including our affiliates, on a going-forward basis, you may opt-out of receiving these marketing-related emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each e-mail.
  * Receiving telephone calls from us: If you no longer want to receive marketing-related telephone calls from us, please let us know when we call you.
  * Other ways to opt-out: Please feel free to contact us at any time as indicated in the “Contacting Us” section of this Privacy Policy to opt-out from email, telephone, or other forms of marketing.

To understand how to opt-out of marketing from our Co-Branding Partners that collect information directly from you, please read the Co-Branding Partner’s privacy policy.

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please also note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, and you cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages.

**How you can access, change or suppress your Personal Information**

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress, or delete Personal Information that has been previously provided to us by you, you may contact us through the Contact us page on our Site or as set forth in the “Contacting Us” section of this Privacy Policy.

In your request, please make clear what Personal Information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Information that you have provided to us suppressed from our database or otherwise let us know what limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Information that you have provided to us For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the Personal Information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. 

Back to Top

### Retention period

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. 

Back to Top

### Use of online systems by minors

The Online Systems are not directed to individuals under the age of fourteen (14), and we request that these individuals do not provide Personal Information through the Online Systems.

Back to Top

### Cross-border transfer

The Online Systems are controlled and operated by us from the United States, and are not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using the Online Systems you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country.

Back to Top

### Sensitive information

Except as provided in the “Consulting Services and Tools Participants” section, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive Personal Information (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the Online Systems or otherwise to us.

Back to Top

### Updates to this privacy policy

We may change this Privacy Policy. Please take a look at the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Online Systems. Your use of the Online Systems following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy. 

.

Back to Top

### Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at complianceofficer@haygroup.com, or please write to the following address:

Hay Group, Inc.  
100 Penn Square East  
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 19107-3388  
Attention: General Counsel & Chief Compliance Officer

Please note that email communications are not always secure; so please do not include credit card information or sensitive information in your emails to us. 

© 2014 Hay Group. All rights reserved.
